# **Megan Ratto**

**Full Stack Software Engineer** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rattomegan | https://github.com/rattomegan | https://rattomegan.github.io/portfolio/ Buffalo, NY | New York, NY

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Software Engineer with a broad set of technical and personal skills from a background in accounting and administration. Consistently recognized for excellence and promoted through organizations. Eager and quick learner, analytical problem solver, focused on efficient, maintainable, and organized code that prioritizes user experience. Adept at grasping new technical concepts quickly and applying them effectively.

## **SKILLS**

Languages | JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python

Libraries and Frameworks | React, Node.js, Express, Django, Bootstrap

Database | PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Other | Git, JIRA, ZenDesk, Heroku, Confluence, Google Chrome and React Developer Tools

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

ArtLab | Pinterest type clone to search Metropolitan Museum public collection

Feb 2022

Technologies used: React, Express, Node.js, MongoDB (MERN Stack), HTML, CSS, 3rd party API, Heroku

- Developed a full-stack React app using the Metropolitan Museum's open-source API, allowing users to search through a digital art collection (implemented basic and advanced search) and save as favorites with MongoDB using a server side API
- Established user sign up and login authentication using JSON web tokens and bcrypt
- Modularized React frontend, focused on reusable components with React hooks and state
- Client-side routing using React Router, including protected routes and path parameters

Resume Architect | Resume Customization Application

Jan 2022

Technologies used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku

- Collaborated with two fellow software developers using mob programming to build Python application using Django framework to customize and save resume data based on job descriptions
- Programmed full CRUD operations using class and function based views
- Drove project definition and application architecture, set team goals, and balanced project scope and improvements with time allotted

**Moond** | Full-stack CRUD period tracking application

Dec 2021

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Google OAuth 2.0

- Built a dynamic calendar application used to track period cycle and symptoms data with full CRUD functionality
- Developed using MEN stack (MongoDB, Express, Node.is)
- Implemented Google OAuth 2.0 to allow users to sign up with their Google account

War | Vanilla javascript card game

Nov 2021

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub Hosting

Built the classic two player card game run in the browser with vanilla JavaScript and DOM manipulation

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**General Assembly** 

Remote

Front End Developer Instructional Associate (Evenings)

May 2022 - Present

May 2020 - Sept 2021

- Support lead instructor by leading office hours, reviewing student code, and providing general lesson support
- JavaScript, Semantic and Accessible HTML, Advanced CSS and Animations

Rover.com Accountant Remote

Collaborated with engineering team to facilitate minor fixes to sitter profiles in Django, resulting in quicker resolutions

- for JIRA and ZenDesk tickets Regularly recognized by leadership for improving the efficiency and accuracy of end-to-end AP process; responsible
- for both domestic and international AP invoice processing and vendor communication
- Contributed to Rover IPO by documenting and implementing internal controls for SOX compliance and reporting

### Tax and Accounting Generalist

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

- Managed customer service ticketing system in ZenDesk for tax and payment related questions
- Calculated and filed between 10 and 20 state sales taxes monthly
- Completed daily payments to sitters, including check tracking and reissues, ensuring accurate accounts

# Zillow Group Inc.

Seattle, WA

#### Executive Assistant to the Co-Founder and & Vice Chairman

Dec 2015 - Jan 2017

- Managed dynamic schedules/calendars, successfully balancing ever-evolving logistics, urgencies, and priorities
- Cultivated and furthered relationships across teams and company personnel; represented Office of the Founders in communication and scheduling with internal and external stakeholders

# Project and Administrative Assistant to the CEO

Oct 2014 - Nov 2015

Managed planning, communication, and logistics for two offsite events for the Top 10 Zillow executives

## **Facilities Coordinator**

May 2014 - Sept 2014

• Developed and implemented system for tracking desk locations and moves for about 800 employees, which resulted in iOffice integration for about 1,300 employees company-wide

#### Front Desk Coordinator

Feb 2014 - Apr 2014

• Championed reporting, database maintenance, logistics coordination, and vendor relationship management initiatives to continually improve department's organization and cross-team relationships

## **EDUCATION**

# Certificate of Completion, Software Engineering Immersive (SEI) Program

Remote Feb 2022

General Assembly

Completed a 12 week, 450+ hour, full-time software development training program to rapidly learn and implement current technologies for full-stack web application development, with a focus in object-oriented programming, MVC applications, REST API creation and consumption, UX and UI, and team collaboration strategies in an agile development environment

# Certificate of Completion, Roots of Western Herbalism Nine Month Program California School of Herbal Studies

Forestville, CA Nov 2018

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Accounting and Business Administration California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo

San Luis Obispo, CA June 2009